Life is an adventure. Don't blow it.
Bubble Boy is a comedy, adventure, romance film directed by Blair Hayes.
Jimmy is a young man who was born without an immune system and has
lived his life within a plastic bubble in his bedroom...
who pines for the sweet caresses of girl-next-door Chloe.
But when Chloe decides to marry her high school boyfriend, Jimmy –
bubble suit and all – treks cross-country to stop her.
Jimmy Livingston, played by Jake Gyllenhaal.
Mrs. Livingston, played by Swoosie Kurtz.
Chloe, played by Marley Shelton.
Slim, played by Danny Trejo.
Mr. Livingston, played by John Carroll Lynch.
Dr. Phreak, played by Verne Troyer.
Bubble Boy is a 2001 American adventure comedy film
starring Jake Gyllenhaal in the title role.
Written by Cinco Paul and Ken Daurio, and directed by Blair Hayes (in his feature
directorial debut), it was inspired by the 1976 film The Boy in the Plastic Bubble.
The story follows Jimmy (Gyllenhaal), a young man born without an immune
system who has lived in a sterilized dome since childhood.
He ventures outside his home for the first time to stop the wedding of his crush Chloe
(Marley Shelton), after she is revealed to have mutual feelings for him.
Swoosie Kurtz, Danny Trejo, and John Carroll Lynch also star.
Bubble Boy was released on August 24, 2001, and
underperformed at the box office.
It received mixed reviews, with criticism primarily aimed at the film's
humor, although Gyllenhaal received praise for his performance.
A musical adaptation, written by the same authors, was first performed in 2008.
The film explores themes of lovesickness, niagara falls, crush, illness, joyous.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.